Hello hello friends, welcome to your own YouTube channel
let's know India
friends and today we are going to talk about
unemployment insurance so
friends unemployment insurance so friends what is it
and many must have heard the name insurance
life insurance and today we are talking about
unemployment insurance so friends this is
not provided by private companies it is a government
institution as you know whatever is made of it,
under this the government has implemented two
types of schemes first launched in Rajiv Gandhi scheme
and in 2018 a scheme was launched in the name of Atal Bihari
so we will talk about that
in our next video but first
we will understand what is this side
insurance and do
private companies also do this insurance
so today we will talk on this topic
so friends according to the report of MI,
if we talk about unemployed people in 2018
then their number was around thirty one in India 21
million people were unemployed if we talk about 2018 and then
subscribe and this is going on
as you know that according to the Thursday and the soil
that has hit the economy, let us
know that if you people
know then  If you comment in the comment box,
friends, Bloody Mary means skill,
if for some reason the company hires you as per its wish
or it does not have any work
and if the company fires you, then
this insurance comes in handy at that time, so it is
mandatory for you to be registered in it and friends, what is appointed for it, is that
you have worked for two to three years
separately in both and in this you will get up
to 50% salary for two years in your entire life time,
if you work in a company
and you become unemployed for two months, then
you will get two months' salary
if you join and there too,
now we have
unemployment allowance for 22 months, if in future
you ever become unemployed again due to any reason for any
period, then from the
salary that is there in this mantra, you get salary for
24 months for your entire life time and
for this, all of them go to school and should be
appointed there, so friends, this is
how it works and we will talk about
private companies also providing this, so
friends, no company of public and private sector gets involved
in it  Neither does
anyone else offer this line; some companies offer
it.
One of these companies is Royal Sundaram, which
sells this plan under the name Home Loan Secure Shell. Suppose you
work in the private sector and do
n't have this insurance policy, and if you already have a home loan,
you
can secure your home loan through this plan. It also has a
time limit, or
in case of unemployment, up to three months. This is what the
company does, so you get time
and your home loan doesn't go away. The company
believes that within a month, all the schools
and their vehicles will be back on track. The other
company, Ghrit, also offers insurance, is of the
same type. And
quick friends, HDFC Agro also has
a plan like this. So, there are three types
of plans. I'll give you the link to the
name of the plan, so you can search for it,
and if you need it, you can do it. So
friends, now we'll talk about
Ghrit. If you're happy with it,
you won't have to subscribe.
Now let's talk.  Eligibility of who is
eligible to claim in this,
if you are sick or unemployed and have insurance,
then you can claim in these circumstances,
if the company
fires you on its own, for any reason,
financial reason, or something else of their own, that is,
you do not fire on your own, if the company
fires you, then you are
eligible for this, if you are self-employed,
working with the company and at that time you are
caught and the company fires you, then you are
not a pimp, if you are fired due to any dishonesty
or due to any mistake done by the company, then
you
cannot claim in this,
if you have any pre-existing disease and
because of that the company fires you, then
also you cannot claim in this, so
friends, even if you
resign voluntarily, you do not come in this category,
if the company fires you on its own, only then
you get
appointment under this, so friends, in this we
will discuss two schemes, government schemes,
in your next video, so like it, if you liked the
video, then share it, subscribe to the channel,
Jai Hind, Jai Bharat